Contact

+380676873447 (Mobile) valentin.sheboldaev@gmail.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/w-e-ll (LinkedIn) w-e-ll.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
PostgreSQL
MongoDB

Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

Valentin Sheboldaev

Python Software Engineer - currently looking for a job

Summary

Hi! Let's start off with me saying I love what I do! I mean, come on - software development is the happy and creative process! I am true Software Engineer professional with knowledge of Object-Oriented Design and Programming who helps IT-companies and loves to collaboratively with team to build and optimize complex software solutions, so that companies can increase revenue and reduce cost.

I'm here to help you find your dream solution – not just a basic one. I'm an extrovert person, the life and soul of the festivity. Help me by letting me help you! I feel that my skills and experience are a good match for your job.

NOW:

Python Development

- 3+ years' experience in object-oriented python application development:
- Good understanding of OOP principles and design patterns, algorithms and data structures
- Understanding of the Agile software development practices such as Scrum and Kanban
- Python, PostgreSQL/AsyncPG, MongoDB/MongoEngine, AsynclO, Threading/Multiprocessing, Collections
- Bottle/Aiohttp, Lxml, Re, Pillow, Selenium, Scrapy, PyTest, Mypy, Logger, Swagger, Git, Docker, Jira, Linux

FAMILIAR WITH:

- Celery, Redis, RabbitMQ, Apache Airflow, Pandas

LEARNING:

Networking Programming

- Broadband Technologies, Network Cabling, Physical Network Segmentation
- OSI Model, Switches, Routers, Powerline Networking, Wireless Bridges for Networking

- Convergence, Network Mapping, TCP/IP and Subnet Masking, Servers
- Troubleshooting Methodology, VPN Virtual Private Networking, Voice Over IP
- Cloud Computing, OpenDNS for Network Security, Bandwidth Throttling with NetBalancer

IN PAST:

SEO. Digital Marketing. Web Development 10+ years of experience. Good expertise in Search Engine Optimization (SEO):

- Setlinks, Gogetlinks, Seopult, Megaindex, Sape, GetGoodlinks, Miralinks
- Good command of Google Pay-Per-Click Advertising management tools
- Content marketing: writing, rewriting, generation of unique content 7+ years' experience in Website Development, Wp-Themes, Wp-Plugin Development:
- Fixed design, Liquid or Fluid design, Responsive design
- CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap, Wordpress, Joomla, (MySQL, PHP, JQuery - novice)
- Landing pages, portfolio, blogs, magazines, directory and contact pages, homepages

Anyways enough about me, let's connect! Email me at Valentin dot Sheboldaev at gmail dot com

Experience

Smartwork Solutions GmbH Software Developing Engineer June 2019 - January 2020 (8 months)

Munich, Bavaria

- designed and developed new system components as a part of the back-end team;
- implemented a custom system for user registration and management;
- designed and developed image processor for concrete image converting strategy;
- implemented import and export APIs for bitmap and vector images;

- added custom routines/jobs for content processing in tables and sections during word import;
- implemented database migrations with custom business logic on application startup;
- designed and implemented RESTful/Websockets APIs with Python 3.7 and MongoDB/Mongoengine.

HotelFriend AG

Software Developing Engineer

March 2018 - February 2019 (1 year)

Berlin, Germany

- developed applications to extract data from Booking, Hotels, Tripadvisor, HotelsCombined, Melia;
- created a robust, async, socks5 proxy, error-resistant crawler to scrape Google App;
- ran 32 parallel crawlers on 5 PC simultaneously, collected over half a million of hotels;
- scraped complete information about the hotel business profile;
- parsed and scraped Google Places using Google Place API;
- scraped search engine results for SEO tracking, collected domains for link builder;
- provided scraped data in formats like: json, csv, excel, xml, postgresql etc.

PNN Soft

Software Developing Engineer August 2017 - January 2018 (6 months)

Kiev, Ukraine

- designed and developed new system components, as a part of the back-end team;
- developed and maintained existing back-end components:
- developed and extended user registration module with new business logic;
- maintained and extended user licensing module and billing module;
- designed and implemented REST APIs with Python 3.5, Flask and MySQL

BIOTECHNIK

Web Developer

July 2016 - March 2017 (9 months)

Uzhhorodskyi raion, Zakarpattya, Ukraine

- designed and developed corporate website, Wordpress theme development;
- back-end application development with complex product catalog;

- ensured efficient and correct implementation of website;
- developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and user experience.
- increased authority and trust-rating of website reputation management;

Advance Kazo Dental Clinic Software Developing Engineer. SEO January 2015 - March 2016 (1 year 3 months) Kyiv, Kyiv City, Ukraine

- website development: front-end and back-end;
- audit and optimization, competitor analysis, keyword research;
- search engine optimization, link building;
- increased authority and trust-rating of website reputation management;
- maintained website and added more appealing features;

Education

National Aviation University

Specialist degree, Electrical engineering, electric power consumption systems. · (1999 - 2005)

School of Internet Marketing EMPO

SEO Specialist, Search Engine Optimization · (2009 - 2010)

David Beazley - programmer, book author, trainer Python Programming Language LiveLessons

Education Center "Specialist"

Object oriented python programming. Basics of SQL. PostgreSQL.

Udemy Online Courses
REST APIs with Flask and Python